Guide to the Stanford University, School of Humanities and Sciences, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, School of Humanities and Sciences, records
1930-1999
1950-1986
SC0036
Stanford University. School of Humanities and Sciences.
Wessells, Norman K.
27 Linear feet
Correspondence, budgetary data, departmental files and surveys, computer compilations, reports, minutes, course lists, and other records maintained in the Office of the Dean. Deans of the School during the years 1950 to 1986 included Ray N. Faulkner, Philip H. Rhinelander, Robert R. Sears, Albert H. Hastorf, Halsey Royden, and Norman K. Wessells.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfers, School of Humanities and Sciences, 1966, 1988 and 1989. Gift of Barbara Finberg, 2006.
Information about Access
Materials in Accession 1988-052, Box 3, restricted 75 years from date of creation.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, budgetary data, departmental files and surveys, computer compilations, reports, minutes, course lists, and other records maintained in the Office of the Dean. Deans of the School during the years 1950 to 1986 included Ray N. Faulkner, Philip H. Rhinelander, Robert R. Sears, Albert H. Hastorf, Halsey Royden, and Norman K. Wessells.
Access Terms
Faulkner, Ray Nelson, 1906-1975.; Hastorf, Albert H., 1920-; Rhinelander, Philip H.; Royden, H. L.; Sears, Robert R. (Robert Richardson); Stanford University. School of Humanities and Sciences.; Wessells, Norman K.; Wessells, Norman K.; Universities and colleges--Administration.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accession ARCH-1988-052
  - Appendices A, B, C - Paul N. McCloskey (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Appendix D - Course Material for the Congressional decision-making Process 1964-83 - Paul N. McCloskey (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Committee Report - Paul N. McCloskey (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Memos: Translators & Interpreters Programs 1970-72 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Reviews of German Translators & Interpreters Program 1970-72 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Accounting System Revision Project (Wessells - 1979) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Near West Campus Correspondence 1984-86 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Historical File - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Committee on Postdoctoral and Doctoral Research Staff - background materials - 1979, vol. 2 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Western Culture Faculty Symposium II - 9/81 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - University Council (Yale Univ.), May 2, 1980 - agenda and committee reports; plus misc. publications from Yale (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 21st Annual Report on Materials Research at SU (7/81 - 6/82) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 22nd Annual Report on Materials Research at SU (7/82 - 6/83) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - A Proposal for the Continuation of the Materials Research Laboratory Program (1982) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - A Proposal for the Continuation of the Materials Research Laboratory Program (1983) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - RESTRICTED ITEMS NOT OPEN TO RESEARCHERS
    Closed for 75 years from date of file.
    - Undergraduate Deanship Seach, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Documents from Search Commitee for Vice-President and Provost, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Faculty Information, -5/31/85 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Senior Survey Confidential Comments and Statistical Summaries -, 1982-83 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Oversease Studies - Chron File - Norman K. Wessells, 1980-82 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Oversease Studies - Director Search, 12/84 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1989-114
  - African American Studies, 1969-1983 (20 files) (Box 1)
  - Anthropology, 1962-1983 (22 files) (Box 1)
  - Applied Physics, 1962-1983 (27 files) (Box 2)
  - Art, 1962-1983 (20 files) (Box 2)
  - Art & Architecture, 1961-1971 (Box 2)
  - Art & Architecture, 1961-1971 (total of 14 files) (Box 3)
  - Art Gallery and Museum, 1962-1982 (21 files) (Box 3)
  - Asian Languages, 1962-83 (Box 3)
  - Asian Languages, 1962-83 (total of 35 files) (Box 4)
  - Astronomy, 1978-1983 (7 files) (Box 4)
  - Biological Sciences, 1962-1983 (30 files) (Box 4)
  - Div. Systemic Biology, 1962-1972 (10 files) (Box 4)
  - Jasper Ridge, 1968-1983 (1 file) (Box 4)
  - Hopkins Marine, 1962-1983 (26 files) (Box 5)
  - Proteus, 1969-1971 (1 file) (Box 5)
  - Black Performing Arts, 1972-1984 (13 files) (Box 5)
  - Boystown, 1973-1982 (10 files) (Box 5)
  - Chemistry, 1962-1984 (28 files) (Box 6)
  - Chicano Studies, 1973-1983 (10 files) (Box 6)
  - Classics, 1961-1983 (22 files) (Box 7)
  - Communication, 1962-1983 (Box 7)
  - Communication, 1962-1983 (total of 25 files) (Box 8)
  - Comparative Literature, 1969-1983 (15 files) (Box 8)
  - Computer Science, 1962-1983 (Box 8)
  - Computer Science, 1962-1983 (total of 24 files) (Box 9)
  - Drama, 1968-1983 (16 files) (Box 9)
  - Economics, 1962-1984 (Box 9)
  - Economics, 1962-1984 (total of 34 files) (Box 10)
  - English, 1962-1985 (Box 10)
  - English, 1962-1985 (total of 34 files) (Box 11)
  - Creative Writing, 1969-1976 (7 files) (Box 11)
  - Feminist Studies, 1984-1985 (1 file) (Box 11)
  - Food Research Institute, 1975-1984 (9 files) (Box 11)
  - French and Italian, 1962-1984 (Box 11)
  - French and Italian, 1962-1984 (total of 27 files) (Box 12)
  - German, 1969-1984 (15 files) (Box 12)
  - Geography, 1962-1967 (5 files) (Box 12)
  - Hispanic American Studies, 1962-1966 (3 files) (Box 12)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1990-070
  - School of Humanities and Sciences: A Report on Academic Space from 1963-64 through 1974-75. Prepared by Raymond Bachetti, June 1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - School of Humanities and Sciences: A Report on Academic Space from 1963-64 through 1974-75. Prepared by Raymond Bachetti, June 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - School of Humanities and Sciences: A Projection of Academic Space Needs from 1965 to 1975. Prepared by Donald R. Price, October 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2006-053
  - Office of the Dean, 1999-2000 Academic Plan, Notebook of materials for the Humanities and Sciences Council Meeting, May 21, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Folder of loose materials from above notebook (Box 1)